In his own words
Tupac: Resurrection is a music, documentary film directed by Lauren Lazin.
Home movies, photographs, and recited poetry illustrate the life of Tupac Shakur, one of
the most beloved, revolutionary, and volatile hip-hop MCs of all time.
Himself (archive footage), played by Tupac Shakur.
Self, played by Afeni Shakur.
Self, played by Snoop Dogg.
Self, played by Dr. Dre.
Self, played by 50 Cent.
Self, played by Eminem.
Tupac: Resurrection is a 2003 American documentary film about
the life and death of rapper Tupac Shakur.
The film, directed by Lauren Lazin and released by
Paramount Pictures, is narrated by Shakur himself.
Tupac: Resurrection premiered at the 2003 Sundance Film Festival on January 22, 2003, and
was released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on November 14, 2003.
As of July 1, 2008, it had earned over $7.8 million, making it the 21st-highest-grossing
documentary film in the United States - (in nominal dollars, from 1982 to the present).
The film was nominated for the Academy Award for Best
Documentary Feature at the 77th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of rap music, hip-hop, blunt, woman director.